二零零五年，普通高等学校招生。
全国统一考试听力部分，该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将你的。答案转涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
试音到此结束，听力考试正式开始。
请看听力。
部分第一节，第一节，听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后。
你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题，
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容。
你将有五秒钟的时间将正确答案标在试卷上。
趁。
山的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择
项，并将其标在试卷上。
现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容
Text 1. Very nice skirts.
How much are $10 each and $1 off if people buy two.
They're on sale.
Text 2. I know you want to about this report, but I'd like to talk about my new
computer. Let's keep to the point.
We can talk about that later.
Alright? Okay. Text 3.
Bill, that is a lovely painting in your living room.
I'm glad you like it.
It's a Christmas gift from my son.
Well, it's beautiful.
Your son has very good taste.
Text 4. So, how is your new roommate?
She really makes me angry.
What happened? She's always making loud noises at midnight.
When I remind her, she's always rude.
Text 5. Excuse me, I'm looking for Mr.
Tang. Oh, he is not on this floor.
He is on the fourth floor.
Go down the stairs and turn left.
That's for the the fourth stairs left.
第一节到此结束。
第二节。
听下面五段对话或独白，
每段对话或独白后有几个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前。
你将有时间阅读各个小题，
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六。
和第七两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Go left. part.
Go down left.
part. Go the left.
left. Text 6.
Did you finish typing that report?
Yes, I did.
But I worked late.
But it must be a long report, I guess.
Exactly. Twelve pages.
I spent three hours on it.
By the way, what time did you go home?
I left the office at nine o I got home at ten.
What did you have for dinner?
I sent out for a sandwich and ate at my desk.
Did you finish typing that report?
Yes, I did.
But I worked late.
But it must be a long report, I guess.
Exactly. Twelve pages.
I spent three hours on it.
By the way, what time did you go home?
I left the office at nine o I got home at ten.
What did you have for dinner?
I sent out for a sandwich and ate at my desk.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至十小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Text 7. Ricky, what's going on?
Fred just told me that you're going to be leaving us.
Yes, I really feel bad about it.
But BND came up with a really good offer.
Well, I didn't know that you were going to look for a new job.
Just between you and me, I think we have some real problems in this department.
Don't get me wrong.
It has nothing to do with you, Frank.
Everybody says you are an excellent manager.
Problems? What problems?
Do we have time to talk about it?
Ricky, what's going on?
Fred just told me that you're going to be leaving us.
Yes, I really feel bad about it.
But BND came up with a really good offer.
Well, I didn't know that you were going to look for a new job.
Just between you and me, I think we have some real problems in this department.
Don't get me wrong.
It has nothing to do with you, Frank.
Everybody says you are an excellent manager.
Problems? What problems?
Do we have time to talk about it?
听下面一段对话。
话，回答第十一至十三小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Text 8. You know, I just finished some very interesting research for the newspaper
about things people do in their spare time.
Really? What did you learn?
Well, I talked to 20 people, and 19 of them watch TV.
That's interesting. I never watch it.
Do you? Not much.
Anyway, about half of them, 9 people, play some kind of sport.
I'm not surprised.
People are getting more exercise these days?
Yes, a few of them go to movies.
I do too.
But here is the most interesting result.
Only one of them reads...
That's terrible. You know, I just finished some very interesting research for the
newspaper about things people do in their spare time.
Really? What did you learn?
Well, I talked to 20 people, and 19 of them watch TV.
That's interesting. I never watch it.
Do you? Not much.
Anyway, about half of them, 9 people, play some kind of sport.
I'm not surprised.
People are getting more exercise these days?
Yes, a few of them go to movies.
I do too.
But here is the most interesting result.
Only one of them reads...
That's terrible. just finished some interesting watch you?
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至十七小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间。
阅读这四个小题。
a few of to That's You much.
Anyway, about them go to movies.
That's Really? I think San Francisco is probably the most exciting place in the U.S.
So do I.
No other city has so many good restaurants or as much good music.
Is San Francisco your hometown?
I am from a very small town in Pennsylvania.
I wouldn't want to live there again either.
I don't like small town living very much.
Neither do I really.
But small towns have their advantages.
Less traffic. And friendlier people.
You know, I'm beginning to feel homesick.
By the way, where are you from?
China. China. But you speak English like a native speaker.
I didn't have any idea.
No, excuse me.
It's time for my flight.
Well, nice talking to you.
Me too. Bye.
Excuse me. Do you mind if I sit here?
Not at all.
Go ahead. Thanks.
Are you going somewhere or meeting someone?
I am on my way to Washington.
And you? I am on my way to San Francisco.
Really? I think San Francisco is probably the most exciting place in the U.S.
So do I.
No other city has so many good restaurants or as much good music.
Is San Francisco your hometown?
I am from a very small town in Pennsylvania.
I wouldn't want to live there again either.
I don't like small town living very much.
Neither do I really.
But small towns have their advantages.
Less traffic. And friendlier people.
You know, I'm beginning to feel homesick.
By the way, where are you from?
China. China. But you speak English like a native speaker.
I didn't have any idea.
Oh, excuse me.
It's time for my flight.
Well, nice talking to you.
Me too. Bye.
听下面一段。
换独白，回答第十八至二十小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Well, I feel it is very important for families to have regular meals together.
One of my good childhood memories was dinner with my parents and two sisters.
Because my husband and I both worked and our three children are busy with their
studies, we seldom had a chance to get together with the family.
But we thought it would be possible for us to sit down and enjoy meals together
every week. First, we tried setting three fixed days.
Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays.
But almost everyone was unhappy.
Then my son had the idea that everyone told me his or her most convenient days and I
would choose the two best days.
For a while, the children were still unhappy with the idea.
They said they would rather spend time with their friends playing sports.
Gradually though, they began to see these evenings together as interesting and
helpful. We laughed a lot.
We made plans for trips.
We discussed each other's problems.
After a couple of months, anyone who had to miss a family meal felt regretful.
And now, we all feel that we have been able to build much stronger relationships
within the family than we had before.
Could you suggest some ways to bring family members closer together?
Well, I feel it is very important for families to have regular meals together.
One of my good childhood memories was dinner with my parents and two sisters.
Because my husband and I both worked and our three children are busy with their
studies, we seldom had a chance to get together with the family.
But we thought it would be possible for us to sit down and enjoy meals together
every week. First we tried setting three fixed days, Mondays, Wednesdays and
Fridays, but almost everyone was unhappy.
Then my son had the idea that everyone told me his or her most convenient days and I
would choose the two best days.
For a while the children were still unhappy with the idea.
They said they would rather spend time with their friends playing sports.
Gradually though, they began to see these evenings together as interesting and
helpful. We laughed a lot.
We made plans for trips.
We discussed each other's problems.
After a couple of months, anyone who had to miss a family meal felt regretful.
And now, we all feel that we have been able to build much stronger relationships
within the family than we had before.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案转涂到客观题答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. you.
听力部分到此结束。